

aakash.dixit@outlook.com

+91 8588928763

Faridabad, Haryana, IN

LinkedIn

Gurgaon

Summary

Over 9+ years of IT Industry experience as Software and DevOps Engineer with interest in developing, automating, and implementing cutting edge technology, open-source tools, and cloud-based services. Clear Quest in Linux and containers (Docker, Kubernetes) environments. Curated Jenkins Pipelines and written shell and python scripts put me in front row to automate repetitive tasks, deployment of critical applications, and proactively manage change with the help of Ansible playbooks and terraform. I'm a highly motivated team player and autodidact with great interpersonal abilities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Capgemini Engineering Pvt Ltd - Senior Professional I

May 2021 – current

Design and implemented appropriate Cloud (OpenStack) environments for 9+ applications under one PCRF (Policy and Charging Rules Function) Virtualized Network Functions (VNF).

- Ensured that the project documentation was created and updated, including design, planning, deployment, and upgrade documentation.
- Managing Cloud environments (OpenStack), automation (Shell and Python), monitoring (Grafana and Prometheus), disaster recovery/backups, and capacity planning of VMs in PCRF VNF.
- Automated the provisioning of Instances and Pods in the cloud environments using YAML and JSON files.
- Have created Docker files which are used to automate the image building and instantiation of PCRF containers.
- Setup Continuous Integrations (CI) pipelines on Jenkins to enable every commit made by developer gets integrated in the testbed environment.
- Once code is manually verified, with the help of Continuous Deployment (CD) pipeline production deployment.
- o Creation of shell script to automate the integration of external elements with PCRF VNF.
- Spearheaded 5+ junior engineers in the team to gain experience in Cloud technologies, processes, and best practices to fulfil PCRF project requirements.
- Day to Day task based on the requirement following the Agile Methodology.
- Troubleshoot system, application logs to debug the real cause behind the issue raised via JIRA tickets.
- Regular interaction with the shareholders (Customers, Project Managers, other product owners and team members) to update the status of the project.

Mobileum Technologies Private Limited - Lead Deployment Engineer

December 2020 - April 2021

Bangalore

- Configured and deployed Revenue Assurance (RA) and Fraud Management (FM) Logic on Virtual Machines running Linux OS.
- Managed automation, auditing, and another tooling for security, compliance, and resource usage.
- Managing Git Repositories and relevant permissions including branching and tagging.

Ericsson Global India Private Limited - Solution Integrator

January 2016 - December 2020

Gurgaon

- Setup and managed a cloud network of 120+ Unix servers in/without cluster with 99.9% uptime in MTN and Airtel project.
- Wrote Python scripts to automatically update system configurations resulting in saving 30% config team time.
- Performing UATs & Updates based on the customer expectations and regular feedbacks with Agile Methodology.
- o Installed and configured IN nodes to constantly monitor traffic bandwidth, memory usage, and hard drive status.
- Built and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into microservices, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed.

One97 Communications Private Limited - Software Engineer

February 2015 - January 2016

Noida

- o Providing administrative support for RBT nodes.
- Collaborated with and garnered feedback from product managers and analysts, and documented user data.
- Created Excel and MySQL query for stakeholders to help business products planners to create business plans to get released in the market.
- Built MySQL scripts to create business KPI reports for business teams.
- o Monitoring alarms using Eagle ticketing tool and resolving the issues within predefined SLA time.
- Monitoring the Servers performance using with performance monitoring tools like iostat, vmstat, netstat,
 etc.
- o Working Experience in Mysql Db, JBOSS, Apache tomcat application servers.
- o Providing assistance to users through on-call for outage issues and Involving in the Bridge-calls for outage issues.

Mahindra Comviva - Support Engineer

February 2015 - January 2016

Gurgaon

- o Handling RBT for Airtel Africa, Vodafone Fiji, Orange Jordan, Omantel Oman.
- o Augmenting new servers, implementing, configuring, and testing new products and services.
- Daily database backups and updates.
- Database and platform migration and purging activities.
- o Trouble shooting technical problems and fixing customer issues as priority.
- Executing complex SQL queries for urgent data provisioning and on-demand extracting information for business teams.

EDUCATION

C-DAC - PGDiploma in IT Infrastructure and System Security, IT Infrastructure

August 2012 - February 2013

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya -

Bachelor Of Engineering, Electronics and Communications

September 2008 - June 2012

SKILLS

Kubernetes; Docker; Python; MySQL; AWS; RedHat OpenStack; Jupyter Notebook; Terraform, Ansible; Shell Scripting; Jira

CERTIFICATIONS

- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- RedHat OpenStack (RHOS)
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)